Smells are all around us.
气味无处不在。
What we know as a scent is a collection of natural or artificial airborne chemicals released from objects.
我们所说的气味，是从物体中释放出来的、飘散在空气中的天然或人造化学物质的集合。
But smell is often overlooked and undervalued.
但嗅觉常常被忽视，也被低估。
So, as climate change and biodiversity loss threaten natural scents, many people may not even notice.
因此，当气候变化和生物多样性丧失威胁到自然界的气味时，许多人甚至可能察觉不到。
Whether or not we pay attention to the world’s “scentscape”, heat and pollution are causing it to shift.
无论我们是否留意世界的“气味景观”，高温和污染都在使它发生变化。
As temperatures rise, man-made substances release more scent molecules, and biodiversity loss due to climate change threatens the plants that scent the environment.
随着气温升高，人造物质会释放更多的气味分子；而气候变化导致的生物多样性丧失，也威胁着那些为环境增添气味的植物。
“If you go to a forest, you have a given environment and temperature.
“如果你走进一片森林，那里有特定的环境和温度。
If that temperature goes a little bit high, the profile of the chemical components in the air changes,” since temperature can affect the amount of smell-carrying gas particles released from substances, explains John Smith, a chemical engineer.
如果温度升高一点，空气中化学成分的构成就会改变，”化学工程师约翰·史密斯解释说，这是因为温度会影响物质释放出的、携带气味的气体粒子的数量。
“And therefore, the perception of how the forest smells changes.”
“因此，人们对这片森林气味的感知也会改变。”
That effect extends beyond forests.
这种影响不仅限于森林。
Snow — already threatened by a warming climate — absorbs different chemicals from the atmosphere as temperatures rise, which changes its cold-clean scent.
雪本身已经受到气候变暖的威胁；随着气温升高，雪会从大气中吸收不同的化学物质，这会改变它那种清冷干净的气味。
Warmer conditions can intensify smells, leading the snow to smell more unpleasant and potentially gather more pollutants.
更温暖的环境会使气味变得更浓，让雪的气味更难闻，还可能让雪聚集更多的污染物。
Climate change is also quickening the loss of biodiversity, threatening to erase certain smells entirely.
气候变化还在加速生物多样性的丧失，可能会让某些气味彻底消失。
When plants disappear, their scents become more difficult to produce.
植物消失了，它们的气味也就更难产生了。
Some scents are linked to cultural heritage.
有些气味与文化遗产相关。
A recent study reported that native communities in Peru noticed a change in the smell of the Amazon River due to industrial pollution.
最近的一项研究报告称，秘鲁的原住民社区注意到，由于工业污染，亚马孙河的气味发生了变化。
Over generations, communities became desensitised to increasingly smelly rivers, a sign of broader ecosystem degradation.
一代又一代人下来，这些社区对越来越难闻的河流变得麻木了——河流越来越难闻，是生态系统更大范围退化的一个迹象。
At the same time, in some Amazonian belief systems, declining water quality and the unpleasant smells will lead to the dispersal of the river’s spiritual beings.
与此同时，在亚马孙地区的一些信仰体系中，水质下降和难闻的气味会导致河中的神灵消散。
The damage to the scentscape could result in harm to both health and spiritual practice.
对气味景观的破坏，可能会同时危害人们的健康和精神信仰活动。
Even though we have other valuable things endangered by climate change, like food access, there is also an element of cultural identity, cultural survival, and history.
尽管还有其他宝贵的东西受到气候变化的威胁，比如获取食物的途径，但气味中也包含着文化认同、文化存续和历史的元素。
If we don’t look at it, we lose all the richness behind it.
如果我们不去关注它，就会失去它背后的全部丰富内涵。